<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-26T11:19:29-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">1866: The Christening of the USS Abraham Lincoln</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/novel/update/2020/04/25/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1866: The Christening of the USS Abraham Lincoln" /><published>2020-04-25T18:10:22-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-25T18:10:22-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/novel/update/2020/04/25/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/novel/update/2020/04/25/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;water-has-memory-it-remembers-the-shape-of-the-containers-it-is-kept-in-even-when-it-later-flows-freely-water-is-alive-although-its-consciousness-is-dull-and-primitive-that-is-why-we-study-how-water-affects-what-interacts-with-it-including-men-samuel-hahneman-the-founder-of-the-science-of-homeopathy&quot;&gt;“Water has memory. It remembers the shape of the containers it is kept in even when it later flows freely. Water is alive, although its consciousness is dull and primitive. That is why we study how water affects what interacts with it, including men.” –Samuel Hahneman, the founder of the science of homeopathy.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1860s saw the rise of the steam-powered metal warship and the fall of the wooden sailing vessel. The French battleship &lt;em&gt;Napoleon&lt;/em&gt; was one of the first of these new iron-clad vessels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;US naval planners were aware of this technological improvement. In the early 1860s a group of officers including xxx xxxx, who was later to command the first American steam-powered battleship the USS Abraham Lincoln, repeatedly approached President Lincoln and implored him to construch such a vessel. At first he ignored such requests but eventually he gave in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battlecruiser USS Abraham Lincoln was the first American steam-powered warship. Instead of guns of various different calibres, as used on capital ships of most nations, it used a single calibre for its main armaments. It had six 8-inch guns in three turrets, one in the center of the ship and two located in wing turrets on either side of the ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The late President Lincoln’s daughter x christened the ship in August 1866, although workers continued to make improvements to it for the next year. There was an unpleasant incident in the days leading up to the christening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lincoln’s successor Andrew Johnson was on board his special train taking him to the site of the christening in Annapolis, Maryland.&lt;br /&gt;
There were other unusual incidents. The glamorous American actress Girty Donderbeck was on hand for the occasion. She saw fit to jump into the water while wearing a white sequined gown. The Navy had to rescue her. She later felt that the incident had damaged her career, although she had only done it for the publicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Johnson’s speech was before the christening and launch because to have had the speech afterwards would have been anticlimactic. Some American ships are launched into the water sideways but the Abraham Lincoln was launched down a greased chute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Abraham Lincoln was the pride of the US Navy. It showed the US flag at trouble spots and at ceremonial occasions within the US. In keeping with the ship’s importance, the Navy made sure that everything on board was first class, including the food. The ship’s stores included Subramanian apples imported all the way from India. When people eat those apples they get happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one does not need to eat apples to be happy. After the ceremony some sailors snuck some showgirls on board and everyone got a little too happy. One of the girls said she would have sex with the sailors if they paid her, but there was no place to do it, so everyone just danced. The fiddler only knew how to play one song, “Roses in the Woods”, so he just played it over and over again and no one cared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A grand time was had by all. It was clear that if the ship ever went down the effect on US morale would be enormous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;t&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“Water has memory. It remembers the shape of the containers it is kept in even when it later flows freely. Water is alive, although its consciousness is dull and primitive. That is why we study how water affects what interacts with it, including men.” –Samuel Hahneman, the founder of the science of homeopathy.</summary></entry></feed>